Hongsuk Benjamin Choi

PERSONAL DETAILS

Phone (+1) 929-508-6991 Mail redstonepo@gmail.com

Homepage | Homepage | GitHub | Google Scholar | LinkedIn

EXPERTISE

Machine Learning and Computer Vision. Hands-on experience in realworld applications of 3D Computer Vision, Multi-modal Perception, Robotics Perception, Neural Image Generation, Motion Capture, Object Tracking, and Data Collection and Annotation.

Over **500** citations, three active GitHub projects with approximate total **900** stars. Published/submitted 10 papers at top Computer Vision, Machine Learning, and Robotics conferences, such as **CVPR**, **ECCV**, **ICLR**, in three years, 6 as the first author. Got **EB1** (Outstanding Researcher) approval from USCIS.

EDUCATION

M.S., Electrical and Computer Engineering Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, South Korea Advisor: Prof. Kyoung Mu Lee	Mar 2020 - Feb 2022
B.S. , Computer Science and Engineering Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, South Korea	Mar 2015 - Feb 2020
B.S., Business Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, South Korea	Mar 2013 - Feb 2020

SKILLS

Professional at:

Python, Pytorch, Pytorch3D, OpenCV, Open3D, PIL, Camera Calibration, Human Body and Hand Motion Capture, Vicon, 3D Visualization, Performance Report, Conventional Multi-View Geometry CV, Image Processing, Machine Learning, Convex Optimization, Latex

Familiar at:

Java, Javascript, Tensorflow, ROS, Android Studio, Python Simulation, Tactile Force Scanning, 3D Graphics

WORK EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Researcher

Main Team Projects

- User-friendly Floor Plan Generation from Lidar Image
- Manipulation Robot System Development
- Reactive Human Tracking/Following with Mobile Robots

Other Team Projects

- Hand-Object Interaction Scene Reconstruction from a Single RGB
- Metric-scale Human Reconstruction from a Single RGB
- Hand Force Estimation from Vision Samsung AI Center, New York, USA

June 2022 - Present

Visiting Researcher

 Data Augmentation for 3D Human Pose and Shape Estimation NAVER AI LAB, Seoul, Korea

Mar 2022 - May 2022

Research Intern

 Neural Human Rendering for an Arbitrary Person with Implicit Function (NeRF)
NAVER LABS Europe, Grenoble, France Advisor: Gregory Rogez, Vincent Leroy

Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

Research Intern

 3D Human Pose Estimation from a Single Image Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, SNU Advisor: Prof. Kyoung Mu Lee Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

 Pedestrian Tracking from a Drone Captured Video Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, SNU Advisor: Prof. Kyoung Mu Lee Mar 2019 - Jul 2019

Teaching Assistant

• Introduction to Computer Programming Department of Business Administration, SNU Mar 2019 - Dec 2020

Software Engineer Intern

• Android App Development for Movie Trailer Play in AR NAVER, Seoul, Korea

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

Start-Up Team Leader & Software Engineer

• WebApp Development for Workout Social Media Publicly launched at App Store & Google Play Store Jul 2017 - Feb 2019

PATENTS

In Process

- [1] HandNeRF: RGB-BASED HAND-OBJECT INTERACTION RECONSTRUCTION SYSTEM (Samsung A2 patent)
- [2] MonoNHR: THREE DIMENSIONAL RENDERING SYSTEMS AND METHODS FROM MONOCULAR IMAGE (Seoul National University & Naver patent)

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] **Hongsuk Choi**, Nikhil Chavan-Dafle, Jiacheng Yuan, Volkan Isler, Hyunsoo Park, "HandNeRF: Learning to Reconstruct Hand-Object Interaction Scene from a Single RGB Image", under review, [ARXIV][CODE coming soon] [VIDEO]
- [2] **Hongsuk Choi**, Hyeongjin Nam, Taeryung Lee, Gyeongsik Moon, Kyoung Mu Lee, "Rethinking Self-Supervised Visual Representation Learning in Pre-training for 3D Human Pose and Shape Estimation", **ICLR 2023**, [ARXIV][VIDEO]
- [3] Gyeongsik Moon, **Hongsuk Choi**, Sanghyuk Chun, Jiyoung Lee, Sangdoo Yun, "Three Recipes for Better 3D Pseudo-GTs of 3D Human Mesh Estimation in the Wild", **CVPR 2023 workshop**, [ARXIV][PDF][HOMEPAGE]
- [4] Gyeongsik Moon, **Hongsuk Choi**, Kyoung Mu Lee, "NeuralAnnot: Neural Annotator for 3D Human Mesh Training Sets", **CVPR 2022 workshop**, [ARXIV][CODE]
- [5] Gyeongsik Moon, **Hongsuk Choi**, Kyoung Mu Lee, "Accurate 3D Hand Pose Estimation for Whole-Body 3D Human Mesh Estimation", **CVPR 2022 workshop**, [ARXIV][CODE]
- [6] JoonKyu Park, Yeonguk Oh, Gyeongsik Moon, **Hongsuk Choi**, Kyoung Mu Lee, "HandOccNet: Occlusion-Robust 3D Hand Mesh Estimation Network", **CVPR 2022**, [ARXIV][CODE]
- [7] **Hongsuk Choi**, Gyeongsik Moon*, Matthieu Armando, Vincent Leroy, Kyoung Mu Lee, Gregory Rogez, "MonoNHR: Monocular Neural Human Renderer", **3DV 2022**, [ARXIV][VIDEO]
- [8] **Hongsuk Choi**, Gyeongsik Moon, Joonkyu Park, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Learning to Estimate Robust 3D Human Mesh from In-the-Wild Crowded Scenes", **CVPR 2022**, [ARXIV][CODE]
- [9] **Hongsuk Choi**, Gyeongsik Moon, Ju Yong Chang, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Beyond Static Features for Temporally Consistent 3D Human Pose and Shape from a Video", **CVPR 2021**, [ARXIV][VIDEO][CODE]
- [10] **Hongsuk Choi**, Gyeongsik Moon, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Pose2Mesh: Graph Convolutional Network for 3D Human Pose and Mesh Recovery from a 2D Human Pose", **ECCV 2020**, [ARXIV][PDF][VIDEO][CODE]

PROJECTS

A Large-scale Dataset for 3D Human Pose and Mesh Estimation May 2020 - Dec 2020 Dataset link / co-op with SweetK and MotionTechnology

 ${\bf HumanFit: \ A\ New\ Large-scale\ Dataset\ for\ Human\ Fitness} \\ {\bf Evaluation\ and\ Feedback}$

May 2020 - Dec 2020

Dataset link / co-op with SuperbAI, KakaoBrain

Human tracking and counting from Drone images (Data collection and Model development) co-op with Ministry of Science and ICT, Korea

Mar 2019 - May 2019

HONORS

Distinguished Master Dissertation Award, Seoul National University, 2022

Selected as a finalist in Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea, 2020 & 2021

1st place and 2nd place at the *without association* track of 3D human pose estimation in the wild (3DPW) challenge, workshop conjunction with ECCV 2020 (1st in a joint orientation metric and 2nd in a joint position metric), 2020

1st place at the Qualcomm IT Tour presentation competition held by Qualcomm, proposed AR-based workout coaching system and selected as a winner by Jim Cathey (President of Qualcomm Global Business), 2019

SOMETHING DIFFERENT

I enjoy bouldering (indoor climbing) with friends on weekends. I go to a gym almost every day. Benjamin is the English name I used when I lived in Bristol, the U.K. American pop and J-pop are my favorite music. At college, I played an electric guitar in a rock band. I used to play LOL (e-sports) a lot.